From the most unexpected place, come a new call for peace
Paradise Now is a crime, thriller, drama film directed by Hany Abu-Assad.
Two childhood friends are recruited for a suicide bombing in Tel Aviv.
Said, played by Qais Nashif.
Khaled, played by Ali Suliman.
Suha, played by Lubna Azabal.
Jamal, played by Amer Hlehel.
Said's Mother, played by Hiam Abbass.
Abu Karem, played by Ashraf Barhom.
Paradise Now (Arabic: الجنّة الآن, romanized: al-Janna al-Laan) is a
2005 psychological drama film directed by Hany Abu-Assad.
It follows the story of two Palestinian men
preparing for a suicide attack in Israel.
The film won the Golden Globe Award for Best Foreign Language Film and
received an Academy Award nomination in the same category.
According to Abu-Assad, "The film is an artistic
point of view of that political issue.
The politicians want to see it as black and white, good and
evil, and art wants to see it as a human thing."
The film explores themes of individual, friendship, israel,
palestinian-israeli conflict, palestine.
The tone is emotional and intense.